{
    "id": "f7d11b9b78814d178e489785a07e8f7b",
    "title": "General Grammar Quiz",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "ffd79fa2941941c8b2f57c1491e141eb",
            "title": "General Grammar Quiz",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Would you mind …………………………….. for a minute?",
                    "description": "An ing form is used after would you mind.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to wait",
                        "waiting",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It isn’t worth …………………………….. to him.",
                    "description": "An ing form is used after isn't worth.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to talk",
                        "talking"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why are you talking …………………………… such a loud voice?",
                    "description": "We say in a voice.",
                    "answers": [
                        "at",
                        "on",
                        "in"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I wish I ……………………………… English.",
                    "description": "A past tense is used after I wish to express regrets.",
                    "answers": [
                        "speak",
                        "can speak",
                        "spoke"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will be happy when I …………………………….. this project.",
                    "description": "A present tense is used in the when-clause when both the main verb and the subordinate verb refers to the future. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "finish",
                        "finished",
                        "will finish"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Winter is ………………………….. the way.",
                    "description": "When things are on the way, they are coming.",
                    "answers": [
                        "in",
                        "on"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Don’t stand ………………………….. my way.",
                    "description": "When things are in the way, they obstruct movement.",
                    "answers": [
                        "in",
                        "on"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t want ……………………………… to him ever again.",
                    "description": "A to-infinitive is used after want. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "talking",
                        "to talk"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He drove in a ………………………………. direction.",
                    "description": "When these words are adjectives, they do not take -s.",
                    "answers": [
                        "westward",
                        "westwards"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We kept going …………………………. until we reached the top.",
                    "description": "When these words are adverbs, they can be used with or without -s.",
                    "answers": [
                        "upward",
                        "upwards",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will write …………………………….. when I get home.",
                    "description": "When write has no direct object, we put to before the indirect object. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "you",
                        "to you"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Your hair needs ………………………………….",
                    "description": "The ing form here means the same as the passive infinitive to be+ past participle. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "to wash",
                        "washing",
                        "to be washed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}